God's algorithm.
Is a minimum spanning tree algorithm that takes a graph as inputs and find that subset of the edges
of the graph, which form at three, that includes every vertex.
So this is very important, includes every vertex has the minimum sum of its among all the tree that
can be formed from the graph.
So we need to connect all the elements of that graph by having a connection between all of these vertices
with the minimum sum of weight.
It falls under a class of algorithms called greedy algorithms that find the local optimum in the hopes
of finding global optimum.
We start from the edges with the lowest weight and keep adding edges until we reach our goal.
The steps of implementing Cruz calls algorithm are there follows sort all the algorithms, all the edges
from low weight to high, then take the edge with the lowest weight and add it to the spanning tree.
If adding that edge created its cycle, then reject this edge.
Keep adding edges until we reach all vertices.
Let's take an example.
Start with a weighted graph.
I need from you to write this algorithm down and this example down in order to understand it well.
We have six edges as six vertices, and we have one two three, four, five, six, seven and eight
edges.
These are the weight of the edge.
So if I need to move from here to here, I need to to think about for like a weight of this and that
cost to move from this to that.
Our mission is to connect all of this graph vertices is in a way in such a way.
If I if we have a here in such a way that we find them minimum weight.
So and if it may be like this, maybe like like, maybe like this.
But without looping.
So we cannot make it like this forum because we have passed from this second point.
We go from here to here to a year or a year and then we pass it again.
So no loops.
And we need to get the minimum distance.
So the first step is start with a way to the.
The first the second step is to sort the elements with the lowest.
Wait, this is the lowest one, and this is the lowest one, two and two out of the smallest.
The smallest.
Wait.
Start by here and we connect it with their short edge.
And we add, so connect it.
Because they are having.
They are having that minimum weight, so we at no.
The step number three is connecting the.
That wait with City, if we go back to that graph, we have two of those.
We have three.
Of Week three, and we have three of wait for.
So the first step is.
Sorting the first minimum.
Then moving to three.
And then we moved to force,
so we had three and then we add the three.
So that way, as I told you, we choose the next shortest edge.
That does not create a cycle.
And then we move to for the wait for and we repeat it until we have a spanning three.
This in this form, we have connected the six edges, the six vertices with the minimum edges weight.
So you see guys two, three, three to four.
OK.
This is the mission and the goal behind they're using their Cresco's algorithm.
Now let's talk about this complexity.
It's time complexity of scale algorithm is lucky.
So here is the edge lucky.
Also the edge.
Now let's implement that crucial algorithm and see in the next video.
And later on, we will.